There are a lot of people online
that you go to for business advice.
Maybe Alex Hormozi,
maybe you bought his books.
Iman Gadzhi, buying a brand new car,
flying private jets.
Even Simon Squibb, what is your dream?
No one's ever really looked you straight
in the eyes and gone, "You are never going
to be as successful as those people." Even
me.
If you're a personal trainer watching
this, I'm sorry, but your chances are
not high. Let me tell you why.
Because I got incredibly lucky.
I'm 35. When I was 27
and I moved to Australia, I was old enough
to say stuff on social media
and people believed what I said.
But I was young enough to not be like,
"Listen, Grandad, what are you doing on a
Facebook Live? Get out of here." I
was also incredibly fortunate that at
that time,
at 27,
which was a great time for me to get into
the educative online video
space, Facebook and videos
and Instagram were just taking off.
So much of everything
that I've accomplished is down to luck.
Literally when I was born.
Not to mention where I was born.
I have an accent from the south of
England. If I was from Birmingham,
no point.
And being from Scotland,
you might as well wear an eye patch in
your content.
People aren't understanding what you're
saying.
Even back in the day,
I used to go to business mentorship meets.
Back as early as 2014,
I'd go to the DoubleTree Hilton in
Victoria, and
I'd be in a room with 250 other PTs,
and we'd all be learning the same stuff.
Make content, put yourself out there,
understand your brand. This
is your appetite.
We were all doing it.
And I remember looking around,
and the only other personal
trainer in that room that's still about
is Jamie Alderton. He's the only person.
But here's the other thing.
All these gurus online saying,
"Do this to make your
first million,
do this to make your first 10 million,
do this." They're all
chatting shit. But it's okay.
And I'm going to tell you exactly why now
in this
video. If you implement what I teach you,
chances are you're not going to
have a drinks brand,
you're not going to live in Australia.
You're not going to have an eight-figure
PT business. You're not.
Chances are, if you follow Alex Hormozi,
you're not going to live in Vegas, get a
hot wife, fly on private jets,
and charge people $65,000 for
an hour. You're not.
If you follow Iman Gadzhi,
you're not going to live in Dubai
and do whatever Iman does.
But the reason it's completely okay
is this.
It's the only analogy
that I can teach you.
If you're someone who sprints
and you want to get faster at running,
you could buy
Usain Bolt's sprint course,
which I don't even know exists,
by the way.
And I can tell you 100%, you
are never going to be as fast as Usain
Bolt, even buying his course.
You're just not.
But that's completely fine because Usain,
although incredibly
gifted, incredibly talented,
incredibly fast, will still have loads
of knowledge that you can apply.
And let's say in Usain's course, he
says, "Do this exercise,
do this sprint drill,
do this with your hands,
do this with plyometrics,
do this with your S&C,
and do this with your
diet," hopefully chicken nuggets.
You will be a damn sight closer to being
faster than you would if you took
on no one. Now,
everyone thinks they can be self-educated,
and in some
respects, you can.
But not even I am self-educated.
I could reel off the five business mentors
that I had to get to where I am today,
but I won't because I don't want you
buying their shit. I want you buying mine.
Plus,
I sat through hours of their lectures so I
can deliver it to you in four
minutes. That's my superpower. In life,
you don't need to have creators or
influencers that you aspire to be like.
You just need people above you
that you will fucking listen to.
Because if you join Usain's course
and he says,
"Do this drill," you'll actually do
it because it's fucking Usain Bolt.
You'll actually do the plyometrics because
it's fucking Usain Bolt.
You'll do the S&C because it's Usain Bolt.
And even if you'll never get within three
seconds of his 100-meter time, that's
fine.
Because what we need to do in business,
brand development,
everything, is appreciate that you
are here, they are here.
It's not about reaching them.
It's about not being where you started.
Because even if you went,
how fast does Usain Bolt run 100 meters?
Let's say he's 9 seconds
and you're 12 seconds.
The fact you will never get to 9 is fine.
Because if you get to 11,
you're going to feel fucking good about
yourself.
If you get to 10,
you're going to feel fucking ecstatic.
Even if you start at, I don't know,
my 100-meter time, 18 seconds.
Getting to 15 is a damn good
accomplishment. And do you know what?
It's not even the achievements
that feel good. It's making progress.
It's not even being super wealthy
that feels good. It's about the progress.
It's not even getting promoted at jujitsu
Even winning competitions,
it's not the fact I've won the
competition.
It's the fact that I can look back
and see how far I've come from being a
shitty
spastic white belt. And no one online
is saying to people that although you will
never probably accomplish,
the majority of you, the things
that these gurus are
telling you, that that is completely fine.
Because all you need
is someone you can look up to and respect,
because when you
respect someone, you'll listen to them,
and if you listen to them, you'll actually
do it. And if you actually do it,
you're going to be in a way better
position.
This is the secret with selling workouts,
right?
All workouts are pretty much the same.
They honestly are.
And everyone's out there going, "Oh, no,
you need to do this periodization, or you
need to do this." It doesn't fucking
matter.
If you go into the gym
and you work hard
and you follow the program, you'll
get the results whether or not it
was Mike Israetel giving you the plan
or fucking
Boris Johnson. Even if I
was to give you bad social media advice
and you were to
turn up and start cranking out videos on
the regular, you would probably improve
the position in which you're at.
And I just don't think people
are giving each
other enough credit.
It's not about being a millionaire.
It's not about being mega wealthy.
It's not about what is your dream.
It's about really not fixating on where
all these gurus are at.
Instead,
you need to look at where you're at
and where your next step is, where the
next stripe on the belt is.
Maybe it's 1,000 followers.
Maybe it's 10,000 followers.
With your email list,
maybe it's getting that first
100 on your email list.
It might not be about your first 10K
month, it might be
about your first 1K month. And
if I go on YouTube,
like I did this morning, it
makes me sick with all these gurus talking
about millions and how you can close 10
millions,
and they're overlooking the fucking thing
right in front of them.
That it isn't about you trying to be like
us. See what I did there?
Tried to put myself with all the mega
wealthy people. Declan, smart hat.
They won't see that at all.
It's about identifying the next stage for
you to get
better and actually just using us as
people you actually listen to.
So that when I look down the fucking
barrel of the camera and say,
"Grow your email
list,
you little twat," because it's not 20% of
your total following, that you
actually go away and fucking do it.
That when I say,
"Go post videos for fucking 100 days in a
row, 100
videos," that you actually fucking do it.
And it's the fact that I say to you,
"Put yourself out there
and stop being worried
about what other people
are going to say in the same industry as
you because
they're the only people
that aren't going to buy your shit,"
that you actually
fucking do it.
So much of all the people I help,
I'll be honest, it's not even that
I'm that good as a business guru.
It's that I call people out on their shit.
It's not the million dollars a month,
not the 10K months.
It's doing the things you need to do,
and you're just not doing it.
There's nothing special.
There's no recipe for success.
I'm only sat here in front of the camera
because I did it for years.
There were days I posted three times.
Checked my Facebook,
I lost four followers.
And it's only if you can push through
that, that you can really start to see
success. And again, here's one
that people aren't talking about.
Success isn't a certain amount of numbers
in your bank account. It's how you feel.
Because you could be mega rich, but
if you feel like dog shit,
what's the fucking
point? But alternatively,
if you just hit your first $1,500 month
and you feel
great, who can take that away from you?
One of the best times I've ever felt at a
competition in jujitsu was when I came
third at blue belt in a comp. On paper,
most jujitsu hobbyists would've
seen that as dog shit. But for me,
the competition before,
I lost all my matches.
I turned up way too overconfident.
I took the comp way too seriously.
The second time,
I went out on the piss the night before,
rolled up hungover, came
into third place, felt amazing.
No one can take that away from me.
And if you can redefine what success
is and stop looking to the metrics of
these
gurus and their thumbnails,
and instead look to how you feel about
what it is
you're doing,
you're going to have a much better time.
And just remember,
when you invest in people's courses,
even if it's not mine and
it's someone else's,
it's not about achieving the same things
they've achieved.
It's just about listening to someone
that you respected that did it before you.
Because you're never going to be as quick
as Usain Bolt, but you'd be a damn sight
quicker if you did what he fucking told
you to do. That's about it.
That's all I wanted to get off my chest
today, actually.
And usually, I point at a video here.
There's not going to be that today.